<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>elections on Resul Umit</title>
    <link>/tags/elections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in elections on Resul Umit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/elections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wind Turbines, Public Acceptance, and Electoral Outcomes</title>
      <link>/unpublished/wind-turbines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/wind-turbines/</guid>
      <description>We study the public acceptance of wind turbines, and its effect on electoral outcomes. Despite a widespread public support for wind energy in general, wind turbine proposals attract a considerable amount of public opposition&amp;mdash;a challenge for any government looking to invest in this source of renewable energy. Our analysis draws on a survey experiment in Switzerland, where the number of wind turbines will grow from a couple of dozens to over a thousand in the next three decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rallies around the flag-draped coffins: The electoral effects of security force casualties in terror attacks</title>
      <link>/unpublished/flag-draped-coffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/flag-draped-coffins/</guid>
      <description>Security forces have recently become the main target of political violence. I examine a natural experiment in Turkey to understand the effect of their casualties on vote choice. Between two general elections in 2015, Turkey experienced a series of attacks that killed 157 members of the security forces. Based on an exogenous variation of their hometowns across the country, I estimate that the government vote share increases in the burial places of terror victims.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication without legislation? A cross-national field experiment on members of parliament</title>
      <link>/publications/communication-without-legislation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/communication-without-legislation/</guid>
      <description>Do legislators communicate with constituents about affairs that they cannot legislate? An influential literature underlines the communication of what legislators do in the legislature to their constituents. This article questions the hypothetical link between communication and legislation. I conduct a cross-national field experiment on members of national parliaments (MPs) to investigate how they behave when ordinary citizens require them to explain what they cannot legislate. Overall, the results show that MPs are evenly responsive to explanation requests within and outside their legislative competence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategic communication of EU affairs: An analysis of legislative behaviour on Twitter</title>
      <link>/publications/strategic-communication-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/strategic-communication-eu/</guid>
      <description>An influential literature underlines how much parliamentary communication of European Union (EU) affairs could offer to democracy in the EU. Yet members of parliaments (MPs) seem unmoved by their potential. MPs are strategic about their communication, and this study questions the suitability of EU affairs to their re-election strategies. Analysing the messages posted on Twitter by regional and national MPs from Ireland and the United Kingdom over a four-month period, this article shows that clear electoral safety and strong political responsibility increase the communication of EU affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2016 Austrian presidential election: A tale of three divides</title>
      <link>/publications/presidential-election-austria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/presidential-election-austria/</guid>
      <description>The 2016 Austrian presidential election was remarkably different than the previous ones in the history of the country characterized by its stable political system. Not only did it open the role of president in Austria to debate, but it also sidelined the two political parties that had dominated Austrian politics since World War II. Alexander Van der Bellen won the election with one of the closest margins in recent history. This article argues that the election divided the country in more than one way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The electoral connection of ministerial selection in the UK</title>
      <link>/publications/ministerial-selection-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/ministerial-selection-uk/</guid>
      <description>Many studies have examined the determinants of ministerial selection. However, the effect of electoral incentives on government post allocation has so far not been studied in the literature. Drawing on data from the United Kingdom over the period 1992–2015, this article investigates the relationship between the selection of ministers and the electoral interests of the actors in this selection process&amp;ndash;party leaders and members of parliament (MPs). The findings demonstrate that the greater the electoral safety of constituencies, the more likely are MPs to have a higher office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Turkish repeat elections of November 2015</title>
      <link>/unpublished/repeat-elections-turkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/repeat-elections-turkey/</guid>
      <description>Following the failure of the parties to form a government based on the June 7 elections, Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan declared on 24 August 2015 that the general elections were to be repeated. With the 1 November 2015 elections—the first repeat elections in the history of the Republic of Turkey&amp;mdash;the Justice and Development Party (Adalet ve Kalkınma Partisi, AKP) has regained its parliamentary majority and guaranteed to rule the country for four more years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2014 presidential election in Turkey</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-presidential-election-turkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-presidential-election-turkey/</guid>
      <description>The election of the 12th President of Turkey was remarkably different than the elections of the previous 11. For the first time in the history of the Republic, the head of the state was directly elected by ordinary people rather than chosen by their representatives in the Grand National Assembly of Turkey. On 10 August 2014, the incumbent Prime Minister Recep Tayyip Erdogan won a simple majority of votes in the first round of the election and became the president for the next five years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
