<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Resul Umit</title>
    <link>/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Resul Umit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Divergent preferences and legislative speeches on Brexit</title>
      <link>/publications/divergent-preferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/divergent-preferences/</guid>
      <description>How do legislators deal with having preferences that go against those of the principals that they represent in parliament? This article analyses the debate in the aftermath of the Brexit referendum in the House of Commons to explore the relationship between divergent preferences and legislative speeches. It finds that legislators who defy the will of their country or constituency are rather communicative, and their speeches reveal higher levels of negativity. In contrast, those defying their party refrain from speaking in parliament, but if they speak, they use a significantly less negative language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of income in energy efficiency and curtailment behaviours: Findings from 22 European countries</title>
      <link>/publications/energy-saving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/energy-saving/</guid>
      <description>Reducing consumers&amp;rsquo; demand for energy is on the agenda of various energy and climate policies. Although these policies are increasingly internationalised in Europe, our understanding of consumers&amp;rsquo; energy saving behaviour remains fragmented with often contradicting findings from single case studies. Drawing on the latest round of the European Social Survey across 22 countries (n = 41,830), we find that many variables have the same relationship with different energy saving behaviours, except household income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public perceptions on climate change and energy in Europe and Russia: Evidence from Round 8 of the European Social Survey</title>
      <link>/publications/perceptions-climate-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/perceptions-climate-energy/</guid>
      <description>A co-authered report on our work in the PAWCER (Public Attitudes to Welfare and Climate Change in the European Union and Russia) project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National context is a key determinant of energy security concerns across Europe</title>
      <link>/publications/energy-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/energy-security/</guid>
      <description>Energy security is an important policy goal for most countries. Here, we show that cross-country differences in concern about energy security across Israel and 22 countries in Europe are explained by energy-specific and general national contextual indicators, over-and-above individual-level factors that reflect population demographics. Specifically, public concerns about import dependency and affordability reflect the specific energy context within countries, such as dependency on energy imports and electricity costs, while higher concerns about the affordability, vulnerability and reliability of energy are associated with higher fossil fuel consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining MPs’ communication to their constituents: Evidence from the UK House of Commons</title>
      <link>/publications/communications-allowance-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/communications-allowance-uk/</guid>
      <description>Everyone agrees that members of parliaments (MPs) should keep in touch with the people they represent. Yet some MPs invest more in communication with their constituency than others. We approach this problem with data from the parliamentary communication allowance in the United Kingdom, where all MPs had the same amount of budget to reach out proactively to their electors. We base our analysis on two fundamental assumptions: that re-election is the main goal of legislators and that communication to signal trustworthiness is one way of securing their re- election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication without legislation? A cross-national field experiment on members of parliament</title>
      <link>/publications/communication-without-legislation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/communication-without-legislation/</guid>
      <description>Do legislators communicate with constituents about affairs that they cannot legislate? An influential literature underlines the communication of what legislators do in the legislature to their constituents. This article questions the hypothetical link between communication and legislation. I conduct a cross-national field experiment on members of national parliaments (MPs) to investigate how they behave when ordinary citizens require them to explain what they cannot legislate. Overall, the results show that MPs are evenly responsive to explanation requests within and outside their legislative competence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With happiness and glory, from your MP: The use of e-newsletters in the UK parliaments</title>
      <link>/publications/from-your-mp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/from-your-mp/</guid>
      <description>This article extends the empirical evidence for the use of e-newsletters in parliamentary communication in between elections. It assesses the effect of electoral incentives and parliamentary institutions on members (MPs1) from all four legislatures in the UK. I find that electoral incentives to cultivate a personal vote increase the e-newsletter usage by MPs. However, being an MP in subnational parliaments or smaller parties decreases it. These findings throw a fresh light on why only some parliamentarians are happy to adopt new and seemingly resource-efficient ways to reach out to voters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategic communication of EU affairs: An analysis of legislative behaviour on Twitter</title>
      <link>/publications/strategic-communication-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/strategic-communication-eu/</guid>
      <description>An influential literature underlines how much parliamentary communication of European Union (EU) affairs could offer to democracy in the EU. Yet members of parliaments (MPs) seem unmoved by their potential. MPs are strategic about their communication, and this study questions the suitability of EU affairs to their re-election strategies. Analysing the messages posted on Twitter by regional and national MPs from Ireland and the United Kingdom over a four-month period, this article shows that clear electoral safety and strong political responsibility increase the communication of EU affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2016 Austrian presidential election: A tale of three divides</title>
      <link>/publications/presidential-election-austria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/presidential-election-austria/</guid>
      <description>The 2016 Austrian presidential election was remarkably different than the previous ones in the history of the country characterized by its stable political system. Not only did it open the role of president in Austria to debate, but it also sidelined the two political parties that had dominated Austrian politics since World War II. Alexander Van der Bellen won the election with one of the closest margins in recent history. This article argues that the election divided the country in more than one way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The electoral connection of ministerial selection in the UK</title>
      <link>/publications/ministerial-selection-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/ministerial-selection-uk/</guid>
      <description>Many studies have examined the determinants of ministerial selection. However, the effect of electoral incentives on government post allocation has so far not been studied in the literature. Drawing on data from the United Kingdom over the period 1992–2015, this article investigates the relationship between the selection of ministers and the electoral interests of the actors in this selection process&amp;ndash;party leaders and members of parliament (MPs). The findings demonstrate that the greater the electoral safety of constituencies, the more likely are MPs to have a higher office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2014 presidential election in Turkey</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-presidential-election-turkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-presidential-election-turkey/</guid>
      <description>The election of the 12th President of Turkey was remarkably different than the elections of the previous 11. For the first time in the history of the Republic, the head of the state was directly elected by ordinary people rather than chosen by their representatives in the Grand National Assembly of Turkey. On 10 August 2014, the incumbent Prime Minister Recep Tayyip Erdogan won a simple majority of votes in the first round of the election and became the president for the next five years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>