<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>surveys on Resul Umit</title>
    <link>/tags/surveys/</link>
    <description>Recent content in surveys on Resul Umit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/surveys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Attitudes towards carbon taxes across Europe: The role of perceived uncertainty and self-interest</title>
      <link>/publications/carbon-taxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/carbon-taxes/</guid>
      <description>While using carbon taxes to reduce greenhouse gas emissions may well be effective, this has recently proved too unpopular to put into practice in a number of countries. Yet, at a time when governments across the world are preparing their nationally determined contributions to the Paris Agreement, our knowledge of whether and why people oppose these taxes originates from a single or small number of cases. Drawing on the European Social Survey (n = 44,387), this article provides evidence on public attitudes towards increasing taxes on fossil fuels to reduce climate change from 23 countries, most of which have never featured in the literature before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of income in energy efficiency and curtailment behaviours: Findings from 22 European countries</title>
      <link>/publications/energy-saving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/energy-saving/</guid>
      <description>Reducing consumers&#39; demand for energy is on the agenda of various energy and climate policies. Although these policies are increasingly internationalised in Europe, our understanding of consumers&#39; energy saving behaviour remains fragmented with often contradicting findings from single case studies. Drawing on the latest round of the European Social Survey across 22 countries (n = 41,830), we find that many variables have the same relationship with different energy saving behaviours, except household income.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
