<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resul Umit</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Resul Umit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Who&#39;s the Boss? An analysis of the vote on the &#39;European Union (Notice of Withdrawal) Bill&#39; in the House of Commons</title>
      <link>/publications/eu-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/eu-bill/</guid>
      <description>Advisory ex ante referendums, such as the referendum on the UK membership in the European Union in 2016, provide MPs with a (more or less) clear mandate from their principal, but they are not legally binding. Implementation thus still requires a legislative act, usually by parliament. MPs therefore face the decision whether to follow the will of ‘the people’ or to decide according to their own judgement, and thus whether to act as delegates or trustees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search your Twitter likes</title>
      <link>/blog/likewise-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/likewise-app/</guid>
      <description>This post introduces LikeWise — a Shiny app that retrieves and filters users’ likes on Twitter. If you are looking for a quick direction, click here for the app.
I use Twitter likes as bookmarks, but then struggle to find the one that I need among them all. Hence I have built an app. It is live at https://resulumit.shinyapps.io/likewise/. It can be used here as well, in the window below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political science journals</title>
      <link>/blog/polisci-journals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/polisci-journals/</guid>
      <description>This post introduces psjournals — a new dataset on political science journals as well as an R package and a Shiny app that accompany the dataset. If you are looking for quick directions, click here for the package, here for the app.
Some might find this dataset useful for teaching, if not for research. However, many are likely to use psjournals for selection purposes — to see where they can submit their manuscript for consideration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing reproducible research papers with R Markdown</title>
      <link>/blog/rmd-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rmd-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Click here for the slides, here for all workshop materials.
My writing workflow has been based on R Markdown for some time. In March 2020, I organised a full-day workshop at Campus Luzern, to share my experience with researchers from the three universities in the Swiss Canton of Lucerne. It went very well.
Since then I have revised the workshop material, which you can find at GitHub. The slides are better viewed here at my website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Divergent preferences and legislative speeches on Brexit</title>
      <link>/publications/divergent-preferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/divergent-preferences/</guid>
      <description>How do legislators deal with having preferences that go against those of the principals that they represent in parliament? This article analyses the debate in the aftermath of the Brexit referendum in the House of Commons to explore the relationship between divergent preferences and legislative speeches. It finds that legislators who defy the will of their country or constituency are rather communicative, and their speeches reveal higher levels of negativity. In contrast, those defying their party refrain from speaking in parliament, but if they speak, they use a significantly less negative language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attitudes towards carbon taxes across Europe: The role of perceived uncertainty and self-interest</title>
      <link>/publications/carbon-taxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/carbon-taxes/</guid>
      <description>While using carbon taxes to reduce greenhouse gas emissions may well be effective, this has recently proved too unpopular to put into practice in a number of countries. Yet, at a time when governments across the world are preparing their nationally determined contributions to the Paris Agreement, our knowledge of whether and why people oppose these taxes originates from a single or small number of cases. Drawing on the European Social Survey (n = 44,387), this article provides evidence on public attitudes towards increasing taxes on fossil fuels to reduce climate change from 23 countries, most of which have never featured in the literature before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wind Turbines, Public Acceptance, and Electoral Outcomes</title>
      <link>/unpublished/wind-turbines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/wind-turbines/</guid>
      <description>We study the public acceptance of wind turbines, and its effect on electoral outcomes. Despite a widespread public support for wind energy in general, wind turbine proposals attract a considerable amount of public opposition&amp;mdash;a challenge for any government looking to invest in this source of renewable energy. Our analysis draws on a survey experiment in Switzerland, where the number of wind turbines will grow from a couple of dozens to over a thousand in the next three decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Scholar ranking of political science journals</title>
      <link>/blog/polisci-google-scholar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/polisci-google-scholar/</guid>
      <description>This blogpost has led to an app that filters data on political science journals, including the journal indexes covered here. Try it out at https://resulumit.shinyapps.io/psjournals.
Here is a list of all political science journals in the Social Science Citations Index (SSCI),* ranked according to their h5-index on Google Scholar.
Google Scholar provides a similar list of top journals in political science, but this includes only the top 20 journals. I was wondering how the list looked below this number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open access journals in political science</title>
      <link>/blog/polisci-open-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/polisci-open-access/</guid>
      <description>I have created a list of open access journals in political science—journals that make all of their articles freely accessible without delay.
Please bear in mind that this is not an exhaustive list and that editorial policies change. If you notice that one or more journals are missing or that one or more existing entries need updating, please send me an email. I would be happy to hear from you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research notes in political science journals</title>
      <link>/blog/polisci-research-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/polisci-research-notes/</guid>
      <description>This blogpost has led to an app that filters data on political science journals, including article types. Try it out at https://resulumit.shinyapps.io/psjournals.
In addition to ‘regular’ articles, some political science journals publish shorter manuscripts as well. They are often called research notes, but the name, and indeed the format itself, can differ from one journal to another. Yet, this definition, by Public Opinion Quarterly, covers a lot of common ground:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parliamentary Communication Allowances: Good for Nothing</title>
      <link>/unpublished/communication-allowances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/communication-allowances/</guid>
      <description>In many countries, members of parliament receive publicly-funded allowances to communicate with the electorate. Some hope that ensuing parliamentary communication engages the people with politics and increases electoral participation. Others worry that such use of public funds might create an unfair advantage for incumbents and affect electoral results. Yet, the consequences of this practice remain unknown. Data from the UK House of Commons suggests that both the hopes and the worries are baseless: there is no evidence that parliamentary communication allowances increase electoral turnout or affect incumbents&amp;rsquo; vote share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of income in energy efficiency and curtailment behaviours: Findings from 22 European countries</title>
      <link>/publications/energy-saving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/energy-saving/</guid>
      <description>Reducing consumers&amp;rsquo; demand for energy is on the agenda of various energy and climate policies. Although these policies are increasingly internationalised in Europe, our understanding of consumers&amp;rsquo; energy saving behaviour remains fragmented with often contradicting findings from single case studies. Drawing on the latest round of the European Social Survey across 22 countries (n = 41,830), we find that many variables have the same relationship with different energy saving behaviours, except household income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfulfilled Winning Expectations Decrease Voter Satisfaction with Democracy</title>
      <link>/unpublished/expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/expectations/</guid>
      <description>Every vote creates winners and losers, opening a satisfaction gap between the two. At a time when concerns are high for democracy, we do not know what exactly leaves substantial proportions of voters&amp;mdash;losers&amp;mdash;dissatisfied with the system. This paper provides causal evidence for the cognitive dissonance theory, which points at unfulfilled winning expectations. With a difference-in-differences design around the Brexit referendum, it finds that the result caused an additional 3% decrease in the Remainers&amp;rsquo; satisfaction if they were expecting to win the vote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public perceptions on climate change and energy in Europe and Russia: Evidence from Round 8 of the European Social Survey</title>
      <link>/publications/perceptions-climate-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/perceptions-climate-energy/</guid>
      <description>A co-authered report on our work in the PAWCER (Public Attitudes to Welfare and Climate Change in the European Union and Russia) project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculating standard deviations for survey subgroups in R</title>
      <link>/blog/sds-survey-subgroups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/sds-survey-subgroups/</guid>
      <description>The survey package is one of my favourites in R.
Among its many other uses, it can compute summary statistics by subgroups. For example, if you have a survey of individuals from several countries with an item on the respondents’ income, you can calculate the average income in each subgroup with the svyby() function.
However, like many other functions in the package, svyby() returns standard errors—but not standard deviations—of the mean values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National context is a key determinant of energy security concerns across Europe</title>
      <link>/publications/energy-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/energy-security/</guid>
      <description>Energy security is an important policy goal for most countries. Here, we show that cross-country differences in concern about energy security across Israel and 22 countries in Europe are explained by energy-specific and general national contextual indicators, over-and-above individual-level factors that reflect population demographics. Specifically, public concerns about import dependency and affordability reflect the specific energy context within countries, such as dependency on energy imports and electricity costs, while higher concerns about the affordability, vulnerability and reliability of energy are associated with higher fossil fuel consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EU press releases differ from their reports on Turkey</title>
      <link>/blog/eu-turkey-progress-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/eu-turkey-progress-reports/</guid>
      <description>The European Commission publishes annual reports on the progress of EU candidate countries, accompanied by short press releases. I find noticeable differences between these reports and releases on Turkey; while the sentiments in the reports have been fairly stable over the years, the press releases often remarkably diverge from the reports.
The Commission’s latest report on Turkey hit the headlines as the worst EU scorecard so far.
To see if there is evidence for this claim, I analysed the sentiments in the EU reports on Turkey since 2005—the year the accession negotiations started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media coverage of presidential candidates in Turkey</title>
      <link>/blog/media-coverage-candidates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/media-coverage-candidates/</guid>
      <description>When Dogan Media was bought by a pro-Erdogan businessman, many suspected a change in the position of its news outlets in the long-run. I compare the tweets by Hurriyet — Dogan’s top-selling daily — in two presidential elections, before and after the sale. I find unmistakable changes in the way the newspaper approached the candidates, increasing its bias towards Erdogan in the election months after the sale.
Most news media are divided into pro- and anti-Erdogan camps in Turkey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What determines how much an MP spends on communicating with their constituents?</title>
      <link>/outreach/mp-spends-communicating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/mp-spends-communicating/</guid>
      <description>A blogpost&amp;mdash;that Katrin Auel and I wrote for LSE British Politics and Policy&amp;mdash;summarising the findings of our journal article, Explaining MPs’ communication to their constituents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AKP in Istanbul investing by political colours.</title>
      <link>/outreach/akp-istanbul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/akp-istanbul/</guid>
      <description>A news report on Ahval about the findings in one of my posts on this website, Government investments in Istanbul</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Istanbul puts the money where AKP voters are</title>
      <link>/blog/public-investments-in-istanbul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/public-investments-in-istanbul/</guid>
      <description>Mayor of Istanbul suggested that he would invest more in the districts where AKP voters live. I analysed his investment plan for 2018, and found strong evidence that he means it: the districts governed by AKP receive on average around 250 million ₺ more from the city. Statistical tests point to a partisan motivation behind this difference in public investment.
Last week, Mayor Mevlut Uysal suggested that his administration prioritises serving the voters of Erdogan’s party (AKP), stating that the new metro lines will go to the districts where their voters live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining MPs’ communication to their constituents: Evidence from the UK House of Commons</title>
      <link>/publications/communications-allowance-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/communications-allowance-uk/</guid>
      <description>Everyone agrees that members of parliaments (MPs) should keep in touch with the people they represent. Yet some MPs invest more in communication with their constituency than others. We approach this problem with data from the parliamentary communication allowance in the United Kingdom, where all MPs had the same amount of budget to reach out proactively to their electors. We base our analysis on two fundamental assumptions: that re-election is the main goal of legislators and that communication to signal trustworthiness is one way of securing their re- election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rallies around the flag-draped coffins: The electoral effects of security force casualties in terror attacks</title>
      <link>/unpublished/flag-draped-coffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/flag-draped-coffins/</guid>
      <description>Security forces have recently become the main target of political violence. I examine a natural experiment in Turkey to understand the effect of their casualties on vote choice. Between two general elections in 2015, Turkey experienced a series of attacks that killed 157 members of the security forces. Based on an exogenous variation of their hometowns across the country, I estimate that the government vote share increases in the burial places of terror victims.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most British MPs used to avoid tweeting about the EU, leaving Eurosceptics to fill the gap.</title>
      <link>/outreach/mps-tweeting-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/mps-tweeting-eu/</guid>
      <description>A blogpost&amp;mdash;that I wrote for LSE Brexit&amp;mdash;summarising the findings of my journal article, Strategic communication of EU affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication without legislation? A cross-national field experiment on members of parliament</title>
      <link>/publications/communication-without-legislation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/communication-without-legislation/</guid>
      <description>Do legislators communicate with constituents about affairs that they cannot legislate? An influential literature underlines the communication of what legislators do in the legislature to their constituents. This article questions the hypothetical link between communication and legislation. I conduct a cross-national field experiment on members of national parliaments (MPs) to investigate how they behave when ordinary citizens require them to explain what they cannot legislate. Overall, the results show that MPs are evenly responsive to explanation requests within and outside their legislative competence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With happiness and glory, from your MP: The use of e-newsletters in the UK parliaments</title>
      <link>/publications/from-your-mp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/from-your-mp/</guid>
      <description>This article extends the empirical evidence for the use of e-newsletters in parliamentary communication in between elections. It assesses the effect of electoral incentives and parliamentary institutions on members (MPs1) from all four legislatures in the UK. I find that electoral incentives to cultivate a personal vote increase the e-newsletter usage by MPs. However, being an MP in subnational parliaments or smaller parties decreases it. These findings throw a fresh light on why only some parliamentarians are happy to adopt new and seemingly resource-efficient ways to reach out to voters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategic communication of EU affairs: An analysis of legislative behaviour on Twitter</title>
      <link>/publications/strategic-communication-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/strategic-communication-eu/</guid>
      <description>An influential literature underlines how much parliamentary communication of European Union (EU) affairs could offer to democracy in the EU. Yet members of parliaments (MPs) seem unmoved by their potential. MPs are strategic about their communication, and this study questions the suitability of EU affairs to their re-election strategies. Analysing the messages posted on Twitter by regional and national MPs from Ireland and the United Kingdom over a four-month period, this article shows that clear electoral safety and strong political responsibility increase the communication of EU affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Austria’s presidential race is heading for a third round—here are the lessons from the first two.</title>
      <link>/outreach/austria-presidential-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/austria-presidential-race/</guid>
      <description>A blogpost&amp;mdash;that Mario Gavenda I wrote for LSE EUROPP&amp;mdash;summarising the findings of our journal article, the 2016 Austrian presidential election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPs more likely to secure top jobs in safe seats.</title>
      <link>/outreach/mps-more-likely/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/mps-more-likely/</guid>
      <description>A news report on AlphaGalileo about my co-authered article with Elad Klein, Ministerial selection in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2016 Austrian presidential election: A tale of three divides</title>
      <link>/publications/presidential-election-austria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/presidential-election-austria/</guid>
      <description>The 2016 Austrian presidential election was remarkably different than the previous ones in the history of the country characterized by its stable political system. Not only did it open the role of president in Austria to debate, but it also sidelined the two political parties that had dominated Austrian politics since World War II. Alexander Van der Bellen won the election with one of the closest margins in recent history. This article argues that the election divided the country in more than one way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPs in safe seats are more likely to become ministers.</title>
      <link>/outreach/mps-safe-seats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/mps-safe-seats/</guid>
      <description>A blogpost&amp;mdash;that I wrote for the Democratic Audit UK&amp;mdash;about my co-autered article with Elad Klein, Ministerial selection in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five years of hard graft in a pub kitchen fired up my PhD.</title>
      <link>/outreach/why-love-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/why-love-phd/</guid>
      <description>A piece that I, while a PhD student, wrote for the Guardian for the series called Why I love my PhD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The electoral connection of ministerial selection in the UK</title>
      <link>/publications/ministerial-selection-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/ministerial-selection-uk/</guid>
      <description>Many studies have examined the determinants of ministerial selection. However, the effect of electoral incentives on government post allocation has so far not been studied in the literature. Drawing on data from the United Kingdom over the period 1992–2015, this article investigates the relationship between the selection of ministers and the electoral interests of the actors in this selection process&amp;ndash;party leaders and members of parliament (MPs). The findings demonstrate that the greater the electoral safety of constituencies, the more likely are MPs to have a higher office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Turkish repeat elections of November 2015</title>
      <link>/unpublished/repeat-elections-turkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/repeat-elections-turkey/</guid>
      <description>Following the failure of the parties to form a government based on the June 7 elections, Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan declared on 24 August 2015 that the general elections were to be repeated. With the 1 November 2015 elections—the first repeat elections in the history of the Republic of Turkey&amp;mdash;the Justice and Development Party (Adalet ve Kalkınma Partisi, AKP) has regained its parliamentary majority and guaranteed to rule the country for four more years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing role of parliaments in EU and the Turkish Parliament.</title>
      <link>/outreach/increasing-role-parliaments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/increasing-role-parliaments/</guid>
      <description>An Op-Ed that I wrote for Daily Sabah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The puzzling case of the MHP.</title>
      <link>/outreach/puzzling-case-mhp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/puzzling-case-mhp/</guid>
      <description>An Op-Ed that I wrote for Daily Sabah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coalition prospects: The distance between the AK Party and other parties.</title>
      <link>/outreach/coalition-prospects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/coalition-prospects/</guid>
      <description>An Op-Ed that I wrote for Daily Sabah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2014 presidential election in Turkey</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-presidential-election-turkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-presidential-election-turkey/</guid>
      <description>The election of the 12th President of Turkey was remarkably different than the elections of the previous 11. For the first time in the history of the Republic, the head of the state was directly elected by ordinary people rather than chosen by their representatives in the Grand National Assembly of Turkey. On 10 August 2014, the incumbent Prime Minister Recep Tayyip Erdogan won a simple majority of votes in the first round of the election and became the president for the next five years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electoral reform and legislative behavior.</title>
      <link>/outreach/electoral-reform-legislative-behaviour/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/electoral-reform-legislative-behaviour/</guid>
      <description>An Op-Ed that I wrote for the Hurriyet Daily News.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Britons, MPs suffer a ‘communication deficit’ on EU affairs.</title>
      <link>/outreach/britons-mps-suffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/britons-mps-suffer/</guid>
      <description>An Op-Ed that I wrote for EURACTIV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is no one excited about the resumption of negotiations?</title>
      <link>/outreach/no-one-excited/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/no-one-excited/</guid>
      <description>An Op-Ed that I wrote for the Hurriyet Daily News.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a post-doctoral researcher in political science at ARENA Centre for European Studies, at the University of Oslo.
Previously, I worked at the University of Lucerne, Institute for Advanced Studies and at the Webster Vienna University.
I completed my PhD in 2017 at the University of Vienna.
Curriculum Vitae&amp;nbsp; Twitter &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;GitHub &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Google Scholar&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Photograph&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software I&#39;ve built</title>
      <link>/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/</guid>
      <description>psjournals An R data package on political science journals, with article types being the unit of observation. It comes with an R Shiny app designed to filter the data, to facilitate exploring journals and their article types for manuscript submission.
 App Package Dataset  LikeWise A Shiny app that filters users&amp;rsquo; liked tweets.
 App  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching experience</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Graduate course  Research design in quantitative political science  University of Lucerne, Spring 2020 Syllabus    Undergraduate courses  Causality in law, economics, and politics  University of Lucerne, Spring 2020 With Alrik Thiem     Introduction to media research  Webster Vienna University, Fall 2017 Syllabus    Workshops  Reproducible research  Campus Luzern, March 2020 Syllabus Slides Materials     Academic websites  Campus Luzern, May 2020 Syllabus    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>