<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unpublished on Resul Umit</title>
    <link>/unpublished/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unpublished on Resul Umit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/unpublished/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Parliamentary Communication Allowances: Good for Nothing</title>
      <link>/unpublished/communication-allowances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/communication-allowances/</guid>
      <description>In many countries, members of parliament receive publicly-funded allowances to communicate with the electorate. Some hope that ensuing parliamentary communication engages the people with politics and increase electoral participation. Others worry that such use of public funds might create an unfair advantage for incumbents and affect electoral results. Yet, the consequences of this practice remain unknown. Data from the UK House of Commons suggests that both the hopes and the worries are baseless: there is no evidence that parliamentary communication allowances increase electoral turnout or affect incumbents’ vote share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfulfilled Winning Expectations Decrease Voter Satisfaction with Democracy</title>
      <link>/unpublished/expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/expectations/</guid>
      <description>Every vote creates winners and losers, opening a satisfaction gap between the two. At a time when concerns are high for democracy, we do not know what exactly leaves substantial proportions of voters&amp;mdash;losers&amp;mdash;dissatisfied with the system. This paper provides causal evidence for the cognitive dissonance theory, which points at unfulfilled winning expectations. With a difference-in-differences design around the Brexit referendum, it finds that the result caused an additional 3% decrease in the Remainers&amp;rsquo; satisfaction if they were expecting to win the vote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Perceptions on Climate Change and Energy in Europe and Russia</title>
      <link>/unpublished/perceptions-climate-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/perceptions-climate-energy/</guid>
      <description>A co-authered report on our work in the PAWCER (Public Attitudes to Welfare and Climate Change in the European Union and Russia) project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attitudes to carbon taxes across Europe: The role of perceived uncertainty and self-interest</title>
      <link>/unpublished/carbon-taxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/carbon-taxes/</guid>
      <description>While using carbon taxes to reduce greenhouse gas emissions may well be effective, this has recently proved too unpopular to put in practice in a number of countries. Yet, at a time when governments across the world are preparing their nationally determined contributions to the Paris Agreement, our knowledge of whether and why people oppose these taxes originates from a single or small number of cases. Drawing on the European Social Survey (n = 44,387), this article provides evidence on public attitudes towards increasing taxes on fossil fuels to reduce climate change from 23 countries, most of which have never featured in the literature before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rallies around the flag-draped coffins: The electoral effects of security force casualties in terror attacks</title>
      <link>/unpublished/flag-draped-coffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/flag-draped-coffins/</guid>
      <description>Security forces have recently become the main target of political violence. I examine a natural experiment in Turkey to understand the effect of their casualties on vote choice. Between two general elections in 2015, Turkey experienced a series of attacks that killed 157 members of the security forces. Based on an exogenous variation of their hometowns across the country, I estimate that the government vote share increases in the burial places of terror victims.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Turkish repeat elections of November 2015</title>
      <link>/unpublished/repeat-elections-turkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/repeat-elections-turkey/</guid>
      <description>Following the failure of the parties to form a government based on the June 7 elections, Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan declared on 24 August 2015 that the general elections were to be repeated. With the 1 November 2015 elections—the first repeat elections in the history of the Republic of Turkey&amp;mdash;the Justice and Development Party (Adalet ve Kalkınma Partisi, AKP) has regained its parliamentary majority and guaranteed to rule the country for four more years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>