<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>energy on Resul Umit</title>
    <link>/tags/energy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in energy on Resul Umit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/energy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Attitudes towards carbon taxes across Europe: The role of perceived uncertainty and self-interest</title>
      <link>/publications/carbon-taxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/carbon-taxes/</guid>
      <description>While using carbon taxes to reduce greenhouse gas emissions may well be effective, this has recently proved too unpopular to put into practice in a number of countries. Yet, at a time when governments across the world are preparing their nationally determined contributions to the Paris Agreement, our knowledge of whether and why people oppose these taxes originates from a single or small number of cases. Drawing on the European Social Survey (n = 44,387), this article provides evidence on public attitudes towards increasing taxes on fossil fuels to reduce climate change from 23 countries, most of which have never featured in the literature before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wind Turbines, Public Acceptance, and Electoral Outcomes</title>
      <link>/unpublished/wind-turbines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/unpublished/wind-turbines/</guid>
      <description>We study the public acceptance of wind turbines, and its effect on electoral outcomes. Despite a widespread public support for wind energy in general, wind turbine proposals attract a considerable amount of public opposition&amp;mdash;a challenge for any government looking to invest in this source of renewable energy. Our analysis draws on a survey experiment in Switzerland, where the number of wind turbines will grow from a couple of dozens to over a thousand in the next three decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of income in energy efficiency and curtailment behaviours: Findings from 22 European countries</title>
      <link>/publications/energy-saving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/energy-saving/</guid>
      <description>Reducing consumers&amp;rsquo; demand for energy is on the agenda of various energy and climate policies. Although these policies are increasingly internationalised in Europe, our understanding of consumers&amp;rsquo; energy saving behaviour remains fragmented with often contradicting findings from single case studies. Drawing on the latest round of the European Social Survey across 22 countries (n = 41,830), we find that many variables have the same relationship with different energy saving behaviours, except household income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National context is a key determinant of energy security concerns across Europe</title>
      <link>/publications/energy-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/energy-security/</guid>
      <description>Energy security is an important policy goal for most countries. Here, we show that cross-country differences in concern about energy security across Israel and 22 countries in Europe are explained by energy-specific and general national contextual indicators, over-and-above individual-level factors that reflect population demographics. Specifically, public concerns about import dependency and affordability reflect the specific energy context within countries, such as dependency on energy imports and electricity costs, while higher concerns about the affordability, vulnerability and reliability of energy are associated with higher fossil fuel consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>