<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>communication on Resul Umit</title>
    <link>/tags/communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in communication on Resul Umit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Parliamentary Communication Allowances: Good for Nothing</title>
      <link>/publications/communication-allowances/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/communication-allowances/</guid>
      <description>In many countries, members of parliament receive publicly-funded allowances to communicate with the electorate. Some hope that ensuing parliamentary communication engages the people with politics and increases electoral participation. Others worry that such use of public funds might create an unfair advantage for incumbents and affect electoral results. Yet, the consequences of this practice remain unknown. Data from the UK House of Commons suggests that both the hopes and the worries are baseless: there is no evidence that parliamentary communication allowances increase electoral turnout or affect incumbents&#39; vote share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining MPs’ communication to their constituents: Evidence from the UK House of Commons</title>
      <link>/publications/communications-allowance-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/communications-allowance-uk/</guid>
      <description>Everyone agrees that members of parliaments (MPs) should keep in touch with the people they represent. Yet some MPs invest more in communication with their constituency than others. We approach this problem with data from the parliamentary communication allowance in the United Kingdom, where all MPs had the same amount of budget to reach out proactively to their electors. We base our analysis on two fundamental assumptions: that re-election is the main goal of legislators and that communication to signal trustworthiness is one way of securing their re- election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With happiness and glory, from your MP: The use of e-newsletters in the UK parliaments</title>
      <link>/publications/from-your-mp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/from-your-mp/</guid>
      <description>This article extends the empirical evidence for the use of e-newsletters in parliamentary communication in between elections. It assesses the effect of electoral incentives and parliamentary institutions on members (MPs1) from all four legislatures in the UK. I find that electoral incentives to cultivate a personal vote increase the e-newsletter usage by MPs. However, being an MP in subnational parliaments or smaller parties decreases it. These findings throw a fresh light on why only some parliamentarians are happy to adopt new and seemingly resource-efficient ways to reach out to voters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
